A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs Division, Vice President, Office Files of Mitchell Sviridoff FA577
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1975-1978; II; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  This series consists of Mr. Sviridoff's chronological files. While the majority of correspondence is between Mr. Sviridoff and then-current, former or potential grant recipients, the files also contain memoranda between Foundation staff concerning grant modifications, reports on grantees by program officers, and accounts of telephone conversations and meetings, among other subjects. Some correspondence describes broader Foundation policies. For example, one letter, dated October 22, 1975, contains an overview of the policy guiding the Foundation's funding of work in women's rights in order to explain the reasons for rejecting a request from Equal Rights Advocates, Inc. to eliminate the matching funds requirement.
  - Correspondence 1975 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1976 (1 of 2), 1976 January-September (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1976 (2 of 2), 1976 October-December (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1977 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1978 (Box 36, Folder 5)